

Luís P. Moura

Rua de Santo André 36, 3800-588, Cacia, Aveiro

□ (+351) 918138670 | 🗷 luisppmoura@gmail.com | 🖸 LuisPedroMoura | 🛅 LuisPedroMoura

Recruitment Team July 3, 2019

Job Application for Software Engineer

About Me		

I am a graduate student in Computer Science.

Having worked in such different areas as Acting, Teaching, Sales, Recruiting, Marketing, Team Leading, and being an active teenager that founded a Youth Group, was a Boy Scout, Musician and Chorus Leader, one might ask "why Computer Science"? I believe that my background allowed me to be flexible, a real strategist and a problem solver. Having to master different skills demanded organization and lots of spreadsheets with algorithms to manage projects and my own evolution. Eventually, programming and developing systems became not only a necessity, but a passion.

Personally, my most recognizable traits are associated with my youth years, as I put a great value on trustworthiness and honor. I am a good communicator, can adapt and speak to different audiences, and deal very well with unforeseen situations.

Why your company? _____

Well, this is obviously a generic cover letter for my Personal Website. So I'm quite excited that you got to downloading my resume. I would like to know more about you, and understand why and how me and your company might be a good fit. Let's talk!

Why Me? _____

As a late graduate in this specific area I bring a lot more focus to the table. The choice for this field was well pondered, so although there is still a lot more for me to learn at this time, my motivation is solid. This makes me interested in understanding the most possible about the job and the company. My success is only the success I can bring to the team.

Sincerely,

Luís P. Moura

Attached: Curriculum Vitae



□ (+351) 918138670 | I luisppmoura@gmail.com

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- Fluent in Java, Python, C/C++, C#, SQL and ANTLR4.
- Good understanding of Linux/Bash.
- Familiar with: HTML, MATLAB, VHDL and JSON.

DEVOPS & MASTERING TOOLS

- Good understanding of SQL and Database design.
- Experienced with Git version control system.
- Familiar with a variety of documentation tools: ETFX, MS Office, Markdown.

NETWORKING TECHNOLOGY

• Solid understanding of Ethernet switching, routing and TCP/IP protocols.

Relevant Projects

The Units Project

Personal and University Project

A Types/Units Dimensional Analysis Domain Specific Language (LINK)

Java, ANTLR4

The Units Project is a powerful Domain Specific Language for creating all kinds of Units that offers an interface that guarantees checked operations between them.

It started as a challenge from the teacher of Formal Languages and Automata asking "Why isn't the type Double enough?". During the 4-person group project I contributed to the DSL design and specifications, and developed the codification and graph structure that allowed units conversion. Also developed a second General Purpose Language (now as The Potatoes Project) which implemented a natural *java/python* like use of the defined units.

Later I took the project in my own hands, reformulated all codification and graphs, improving efficiency, correctness and separating the units engine completely into a stand-alone DSL that can now be used in any other project. The subsequent GPL was improved and is a work in progress.

The Cheddar Project University Project

PAC-MAN ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE SURVIVAL ALGORITHM (LINK)

Al, Python

Version 1 started as a 3-person group project for Introduction to Artificial Intelligence with the challenge of creating an algorithm that enabled PAC-MAN to complete a traditional maze having a time constraint for calculations. I took the responsibility of developing the logic and strategy, which resulted in one of the most complex yet effective algorithms of the class, layered with map topography and situation analysis, strategy advisory and validation. It scored consistently about 20% above the second place. Then a small bug in the maze analysis in the last evaluation undercut our grade. Enter version 2.

Version 2 was an individual delivery of a second project for grade re-evaluation, created from scratch in 3 days. The algorithm was not the most efficient one, but the new strategy yielded very good overall results, improving final class grade.

The Blueberry Project

Personal and University Project

Blue Budget - Personal Finances Manager (LINK)

SQL Server, C#

This was a very personal project to me. When the need of studying again at 30 years old came to be, the decision on a Computer Engineering course was heavily influenced by an Excel spreadsheet I've created and had been improving for years. The complexity of information and calculations presented in a quite simple way, was a matter of pride to me.

This 2-person group project from the classes of Databases and Human-Computer Interaction, is the start of the next step for that spreadsheet.

My contribution was heavier in the Conceptual an Relational Model creation, and later I was responsible for implementing all the Database, and a simple Windows Forms interface to showcase its use.

Work Experience in Computer Engineering

SOFTWARE ENGINEER ?-?

Education

Graduation in Computer Engineering and Telematics

Aveiro - Portugal

UA - UNIVERSIDADE DE AVEIRO

Sept. 2016 - July 2019

- **Programming** Computers Laboratory. Object Oriented Programming I, II and III. Formal Languages and Automates. Operating Systems. Human-Computer Interaction. Introduction to Databases.
- Algorithms Object Oriented Programming II. Probabilistic Methods for Computer Engineering. Complexity and Algorithms. Artificial Intelligence
- Computer Architecture Introduction to Digital Systems. Digital Systems Laboratory. Computer Architecture I and II
- Networks Networks Fundamentals. Networks Architecture.
- Engineering Linear Algebra and Analytic Geometry. Calculus I and II. Discrete Math. Mechanics and Electromagnetic Fields. Electronic Systems.
- Computer Engineering Project System Modeling and Analysis. Final Project in Computer Engineering.
- Final Score: 16/20

Graduation in Theatrical Studies - Acting

Porto - Portugal Sept. 2003 - July 2007

ESMAE - ESCOLA SUPERIOR DE MÚSICA E ARTES DO ESPECTÁCULO

Acting and improvisation. Dance and Movement. History and Drama. Music and Singing.

• Final Score: 15/20

Training.

Practitioner of NLP (Neuro-Linguistic Programming)

Porto

IHTP - I HAVE THE POWER

2014

- · How to Create better Objectives.
- Implementation of Performance Improvement Strategies.
- Efficient and Effective Communication Competence.
- NLP Therapy.

High Performance with NLP (Neuro-Linguistic Programming)

Porto

IHTP - I HAVE THE POWER

2013

• Development of personal skill for better performance in human relations (sales oriented)

Pedagogical Training of Trainers

Aveiro

2008

FDTI - Fundação para a Divulgação das Tecnologias de Informação

Obtained official Portuguese Certificate of Pedagogical Aptitude. Allows application for public teaching positions.

Work Experience in Other Areas

JOM / SuperDecor / NOPTIS (NOS Telecom) / Aupper (Publishing Company)

Aveiro

STORE AND DOOR-TO-DOOR SALESMAN

2015 - 2016

• Customer service and Sales. #1 salesman every month. Customer follow-up

Yves Rocher / Vegas Cosmetics

Aveiro, Portugal

2010 - 2015

TEAM LEADER - TRAINER - SPEAKER

- Recruitment of salespeople.
- Team and contacts Management.
- · Technical and leadership training.
- Website Creation and Management. Email Marketing Campaigns.
- Technical Presentation of product in professional spaces.
- · Workshops and Company presentations.

Start-Teatro / Efémero / Viagem Medieval de Santa Maria da Feira / EPA - Escola Profissional de Aveiro / IEC - Instituto para a Educação e Cidadania

Aveiro

Actor - Performer - Teacher 2009 - 2013

- Invited actor and Leading Actor in multiple plays.
- Drama classes to multiple groups with ranging ages from 5 to 65.

Other Activities _____

Scouts Aveiro Aveiro

AGRUPAMENTO 779 CACIA 1990 - 2007

- Development of social skills.
- Team work and team leading.
- Preparation for adulthood.

Youth Group Aveiro

GRUJOCA - Grupo de Jovens de Cacia 1999 - 2007

- Founder of the group at 14 years old.
- Organization of cultural and sports Events.

Ciclo-Paper Rally.

Talent Shows.

Beauty Pageant Contests.

Solidarity Campaigns.

Cultural Events.

Piano Lessons Aveiro

PRIVATE AND CASA DO POVO DE CACIA 1991 - 2003